Guide to the Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses, 1974-2015
Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses, 1974-2015
- Series XVI. 2001
  - Betty Sun: Understanding the Prevalence and Management of Type 2 Diabetes in Participants of Cornell Cooperative Extension Nutrition Programs for the Low-Income Population, 2001, 2566
  - David Solarz: Catch-up Growth in HIV-infected Children, 2001, 2566
  - Janelle Luk: Fluctuation of Energy Expenditure of Physical Behavioral Activity Throughout the Menstral Cycle, 2001, 2566
  - Jennifer Rockfeld: The Effects of Inert and Active Placebos Labeled as Appetite Suppressants on Subsequent Intake and Hunger During a Midday Meal, 2001, 2566
  - Johnathon Kirschner: The Efficacy of One or Two High Protein Meals in Decreasing Appetite and Intake at Subsequent Meals, 2001, 2566
  - Lauren Sebastiano: Cytotoxic Potential of Popular Herbal Supplements of North America Against Breast Cancer, 2001, 2566
  - Mindy Hu: Effects of Dietary Protein of Sulfur Amino Acid Level on the Regulation of Cysteinesulfinate Decarboxylase in Rat Liver, Lung, Kidney, and Brain in vivo, 2001, 2566
  - Nick Bodor: Mothers' Food Perceptions for the Physical and Emotional Well-Being of Their Children and Themselves, 2001, 2566
  - Nicole Hyler: Male-Female Differences in Perceptions of Eating Environments, 2001, 2566
  - Shilpa Londu: A Study of the Constraints on Ethical Decision Making: A New Approach to the End-of-Life Care Healthcare System, 2001, 2566
  - Suganya Karuppana: Why Women Who Deliver at Bassett Healthcare Stop Breastfeeding So Much Earlier Than is Recommended?, 2001, 2566
  - Talia Ben-Jacob: Seeing the World Through Rose-Colored Glasses: The Effect of Individual Differences in Vision and the Relation of Cheerfulness to Visual and Musical Appreciation, 2001, 2566
  - Ann Mizumoto: Estimated Lives Saved: An Examination of the Deviation from Global Equations Relating Child Mortality to Malnutrition, 2001, 2567
- Series XVII. 2002
  - Christine Aguiar: How Message Regarding Body Image Affect Female Hispanic College Students, 2002, 2567
  - Christopher Hickey: Purification and Characterization of a Recombinant Cysteine Dioxygenase and an Investigation of the Multiple Species Observed for Cysteine Dioxygenase upon SDS Polyacrylamide Gel Electrophoresis, 2002, 2567
  - Gregory Costanza: The Effect of Cholesterol on the Membrane Phase Behavior of DSPC/DOPC Using Confocal Fluorescence Micropsy, 2002, 2567
  - Jacqueline de Marchena: Developmental Lead Exposure and Attentional Dysfunction: Possible Cholinergic Contributions, 2002, 2567
  - Michelle Sckolnick: Understanding the Educational and Management of Type 2 Diabetes in Low-Income Individuals Participating in Cooperative Extension Programs, 2002, 2567
  - Rachel Rubin: The Relation of Serum Antioxidants to Asthma in Youth, 2002, 2567
  - Sean Molino Esmende: The Relationship Between Human NRAMP1 Promoter Polymorphisms and Serum Iron Indicators, 2002, 2567
- Series XXVIII. 2004
  - Anna Milman: Understanding Differential Improvement Among Countries in Child Stunting, 2004, 2568
  - Corinne Postle: Body Satisfaction of College Students, 2004, 2568
  - Dan Hart: The Baringo Nutrition Study, 2004, 2568
  - Irving Jose Zamora: Infectious Causes of Anemia in Young African Children, 2004, 2568
  - Jessica Garay: Preventing Weight Gain in Freshman Female College Students: The Effectiveness of a Two-Method Approach to Weight Maintenance, 2004, 2568
  - Joann Kang: The Expression and Purification of Glutamate Cysteine Ligase (GCL) to Generate Antibody for the Study of the Nutrient-Induced Regulation of GCL and the Role of Cysteine Status, 2004, 2568
  - Jyoti Sharma: Effects of Pyridoxal 5'-Phosphate on Cytoplasmic Serine Hydroxymethyltransferase Stability, 2004, 2568
  - Lindsey Giserman: Food Choice Events and Consumption of Fruits and Vegetables over Seven Consecutive Days Among Adults Working in Non-Professional, Non-managerial Positions, 2004, 2568
  - Nida Chaudhary: Factors Affecting the Duration of Breastfeeding in the Population Served by Bassett Healthcare in Cooperstown, NY: Why are Women Stopping so Early?, 2004, 2568
- Series XXIX. 2012
  - Assessing Community Readiness to Prevent Childhood Obesity Through Community Collaborations Using a Case Study Approach in Two Sites. Meredith Burcyk 2012, 2569
  - An Examination of the Effect of Nutrition Labels on Food Sales and Food Purchasing Behavior Among Cornell Students. Catherine Cioffi 2012, 2569
  - Consumption of a Normal Mixed Diet Plus a Folic Acid-Containing Prenatal Supplement Leads to “Supra-Nutritional” Folate Status in Third Trimester Pregnant and Lactating Women. Margaret Dennin 2012, 2569
  - Expression of Fatty Acid Desaturase Alternative Transcripts (FADS AT) in Domestic Piglets Supplemented with Arachidonic (n-6) and Docosahexaenoic (n-3) Fatty Acids. Ian Downs 2012, 2569
  - Quantification of an Uncultered Bacterial Phylum in the Gut. Elle Glenny 2012, 2569
  - Expression of Downstream Targets of mTOR in Response to a Model of Maternal Undernutrition and Hypoxia. Jessie Groth 2012, 2569
  - The Effect of Parental Feeding Styles and Income on 12- and 24-Month Old Children’s BMI. Steven Han 2012, 2569
  - Characterization of Antral Follicle Populations in Women with Polycystic Ovary Syndrome Using 2- and 3- Dimensional Ultrasonography. Brittany Jarrett 2012, 2569
  - Predictors of Variation in response to Vitamin E Supplementation. John LaBarre 2012, 2569
  - Correlation of Placental 1-Alpha-Hydroxylase and 24-Hydroxylase Expression with Circulating Calcitropic Hormone Concentrations in Pregnant Adolescents and Their Neonates. Shuang Li 2012, 2569
  - Functional Analysis of Ribosomal Proteins Using Systemic RNA Interference in Mammalian Cells. Haerin Paik 2012, 2569
  - Comparison of three methods to quantify repair cartilage collagen orientation. Keir Ross 2012, 2569
  - Choline, Genotype, and Personalized Nutrition. Kelsey Shields 2012, 2569
  - Fuzzy Trace Theory, Personality Differences, and Regional Brain Volume: A VBM Study. Catherine Wassef 2012, 2569
  - A Dietary Analysis of Haitian Infants and a Critical Analysis of Dietary Quality Using Nutrient Analysis, Dietary Diversity, and IYCF Standards. Lauren Webster 2012, 2569
  - Acetylcholine System in Rat is Not Engaged in Low Concentration Odor Detection. Monica Youssef 2012, 2569
  - The Effects of Darkness on Food Consumption. Hana Yu 2012, 2569
- Series XXX. 2013
  - Examining Preschool-aged Children's Knowledge of the Five Basic Food Groups. Aarti Agarwal 2013, 2569
  - Choline and Hypoxia Differentially Modulate the Angiogenic Balance in Cultured Human Trohphoblasts. Ben Andrew 2013, 2569
  - Maternal Overweight/Obesity as a Modifier in the Association Between Postpartum Work Behavior and Breastfeeding Behavior. Carlie Arbaugh 2013, 2569
  - Characterization of Circulating Levels and Gene Expression Patterns of Adiponectin, Leptin, Visfatin, and Retinol Binding Protein 4 in Women with Polycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS). Nina Clark 2013, 2569
  - Choline Inadequacy Increases the Expression of sFLT-1. Anita Ganti 2013, 2569
  - Investigation of the Expression and Role of Feline Leukemia Virus Subgroup C Receptor 2 (FLVCR2) in the Placentas of Pregnant Adolescents. Olivia Lee 2013, 2569
  - Studying the Cross-talk Between Nonmuscle Myosin IIA and IRE1a. XiaoQing Li 2013, 2569
  - Evaluating Fuzzy Trace Theory and Theory of Reasoned Action/ Planned Behavior and their Application to Fitness and Diet Decision-Making in Young Adults. Emily Lopes 2013, 2569
  - The Effect of Memory on Snack Intake. Neeta Malviya 2013, 2569
  - Regulation of Curli Expression in Escherichia Coli by YieP, an Uncharacterized GntR-Like Transcriptional Regulator. Rudy Nazitto 2013, 2569
  - Iron Deficiency and Physical Activity After a Dietary Iron Intervention in Female Indian Tea Pickers. Yosmel Serrano 2013, 2569
  - Food Prime Effects on Eating Behavior in Preschool Children. Hilary Soohoo 2013, 2569
  - A Fuzzy-Trace Theory Approach to Vaccination Decisions. Julie Steinberg 2013, 2569
- Series XXXI. 2014
  - Ovarian Size and Stromal Characteristics Across the Phenotypic Spectrum of PCOS. Nikhita Chahal 2014, 2569
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Stress of College and Dietary Consumption in College Students. Frankie Chan 2014, 2569
  - The Effects of Independent and Combined Lifestyle Correlates on Cognition in Individuals with Mild Cognitive Impairment. Twinkle Kuldip Contractor 2014, 2569
  - The Effect of Subliminal Health Priming on Food Intake. Michelle Duong 2014, 2569
  - Umbilical Cord Coiling in High-Risk Pregnancies: Associations with Iron Status. Jocelyn Star Durlacher 2014, 2569
  - The Apparent Transient Reset of Protein Homeostasis at Basal States in Myeloid-Specific SEL1L Knockout Mouse Models. Steven Ham 2014, 2569
  - Anti-Műllerian Hormone Expression is Increased Photoregressed Ovaries in Molting Hens, Gallus gallus. Kristin Anne Hildebrandt 2014, 2569
  - Use of the Social Transmission of Food Preference Task to Test Putative Therapies in the Ts65Dn Mouse Model of Down Syndrome. Scott Euisuk Kim 2014, 2569
  - Gestational Iron Deficiency is Associated with Pica Behaviors in Adolescents. Rachel Allison Lumish 2014, 2569
  - Healthy Meals in Partnership with Head Start. Nancy Laurel Machado 2014, 2569
  - Draw Your Dinner: A Longitudinal Study of Perceptions of Meal Size with Different Plate Sizes. Jennifer Marie St. Peter 2014, 2569
  - SelL-Hrd1-Mediated OS9 Degradation During Endoplasmic Reticulum Stress. Xin (Erika) Shu 2014, 2569
  - Satisfaction with an Online Weight Gain Intervention for Women During Pregnancy. Jiayi Xu 2014, 2569
- Series XXXII. 2015
  - Determinants of Placental Glucose Transporter 1 (GLUT1) Expression and its Relation to Fetal Adiposity in Pregnant Adolescents. Nonyerem Acholonu 2015, 2569
  - The Relationship between Nutritional Status and Physical Activity in Indian children. Brendan Denvir 2015, 2569
  - Effect of Maternal Choline Supplementation on Placental Angiogenic Factor Expression in a Mouse Model of Placental Insufficiency. Vladislav Fomin 2015, 2569
  - Reactions to Self-Weighing by Gender. Uttara (Tara) Gadde 2015, 2569
  - The Relationship Between The Heme Transporter, Heme-Responsive Gene 1, and Transferrin Receptor in Placental Tissue From Women Carrying Multiples. Jonathan Galati 2015, 2569
  - Microlesions and Alzheimer’s Disease: Effects of microvascular occlusions on β-amyloid plaques in normal diet mice versus high fat diet mice. Yurim (Jane) Lee 2015, 2569
  - Methylenetetrahydrofolate dehydrogenase localizes to the nucleus and is a target for arsenic trioxide. Rebecca Liebenthal 2015, 2569
  - Auto-Corrective Response of Ad Libitum Food Intake Over 30 Period. Ji Eun (Raea) Limb 2015, 2569
  - Investigating Placental Calcium Transporter Expression and Calcitropic Hormones in Pregnant Adolescents. Joyce Mathew 2015, 2569
  - Cognitive Function in Polycystic Ovary Syndrome. Reid Mergler 2015, 2569
  - Age, Outcome Expectations, and Willingness to undergo Joint Replacement Surgery: The Role of Time Horizons and Aging Stereotypes. Shayna Ratner 2015, 2569
  - Testing and revision of a survey tool used to assess previous food insecurity experiences. Tracey Rosa 2015, 2569
  - Comparison of three different Vssc mutations that confer insecticide resistance in Musca domestica. Khanh Phuong Tong 2015, 2569
  - Mothers' Use of Social Media to Understand and Inform Their Practices for Pumping Human Milk and Feeding Pumped Milk to Their Infants. Rei Yamada 2015, 2569